In the United States, there are 60,000 people who have a pacemaker that connects to the Internet. The defibrillators allow a physician at a distance to give a shock to a heart in case a patient needs it. But if you don't need it, and somebody else gives you the shock, it's not a good thing. Of course, we're going to go even deeper than the human body. We're going down to the cellular level these days. Up until this point, all the technologies I've been talking about have been silicon-based, ones and zeroes, but there's another operating system out there: the original operating system, DNA. And to hackers, DNA is just another operating system waiting to be hacked. It's a great challenge for them. There are people already working on hacking the software of life, and while most of them are doing this to great good and to help us all, some won't be. So how will criminals abuse this? Well, with synthetic biology you can do some pretty neat things. For example, I predict that we will move away from a plant-based narcotics world to a synthetic one. Why do you need the plants anymore? You can just take the DNA code from marijuana or poppies or coca leaves and cut and past that gene and put it into yeast, and you can take those yeast and make them make the cocaine for you, or the marijuana, or any other drug. So how we use yeast in the future is going to be really interesting. In fact, we may have some really interesting bread and beer as we go into this next century. The cost of sequencing the human genome is dropping precipitously. It was proceeding at Moore's Law pace, but then in 2008, something changed. The technologies got better, and now DNA sequencing is proceeding at a pace five times that of Moore's Law. That has significant implications for us. It took us 30 years to get from the introduction of the personal computer to the level of cybercrime we have today, but looking at how biology is proceeding so rapidly, and knowing criminals and terrorists as I do, we may get there a lot faster with biocrime in the future. It will be easy for anybody to go ahead and print their own bio-virus, enhanced versions of ebola or anthrax, weaponized flu. We recently saw a case where some researchers made the H5N1 avian influenza virus more potent. It already has a 70 percent mortality rate if you get it, but it's hard to get. Engineers, by moving around a small number of genetic changes, were able to weaponize it and make it much more easy for human beings to catch, so that not thousands of people would die, but tens of millions. You see, you can go ahead and create new pandemics, and the researchers who did this were so proud of their accomplishments, they wanted to publish it openly so that everybody could see this and get access to this information. But it goes deeper than that. DNA researcher Andrew Hessel has pointed out quite rightly that if you can use cancer treatments, modern cancer treatments, to go after one cell while leaving all the other cells around it intact, then you can also go after any one person's cell. Personalized cancer treatments are the flip side of personalized bioweapons, which means you can attack any one individual, including all the people in this picture. How will we protect them in the future? What to do? What to do about all this? That's what I get asked all the time. For those of you who follow me on Twitter, I will be tweeting out the answer later on today. (Laughter) Actually, it's a bit more complex than that, and there are no magic bullets. I don't have all the answers, but I know a few things. In the wake of 9/11, the best security minds put together all their innovation and this is what they created for security. If you're expecting the people who built this to protect you from the coming robopocalypse — (Laughter) — uh, you may want to have a backup plan. (Laughter) Just saying. Just think about that. (Applause) Law enforcement is currently a closed system. It's nation-based, while the threat is international. Policing doesn't scale globally. At least, it hasn't, and our current system of guns, border guards, big gates and fences are outdated in the new world into which we're moving. So how might we prepare for some of these specific threats, like attacking a president or a prime minister? This would be the natural government response, to hide away all our government leaders in hermetically sealed bubbles. But this is not going to work. The cost of doing a DNA sequence is going to be trivial. Anybody will have it and we will all have them in the future. So maybe there's a more radical way that we can look at this. What happens if we were to take the President's DNA, or a king or queen's, and put it out to a group of a few hundred trusted researchers so they could study that DNA and do penetration testing against it as a means of helping our leaders? Or what if we sent it out to a few thousand? Or, controversially, and not without its risks, what happens if we just gave it to the whole public? Then we could all be engaged in helping. We've already seen examples of this working well. The Organized Crime and Corruption Reporting Project is staffed by journalists and citizens where they are crowd-sourcing what dictators and terrorists are doing with public funds around the world, and, in a more dramatic case, we've seen in Mexico, a country that has been racked by 50,000 narcotics-related murders in the past six years. They're killing so many people they can't even afford to bury them all in anything but these unmarked graves like this one outside of Ciudad Juarez. What can we do about this? The government has proven ineffective. So in Mexico, citizens, at great risk to themselves, are fighting back to build an effective solution. They're crowd-mapping the activities of the drug dealers. Whether or not you realize it, we are at the dawn of a technological arms race, an arms race between people who are using technology for good and those who are using it for ill. The threat is serious, and the time to prepare for it is now. I can assure you that the terrorists and criminals are. My personal belief is that, rather than having a small, elite force of highly trained government agents here to protect us all, we're much better off having average and ordinary citizens approaching this problem as a group and seeing what we can do. If we all do our part, I think we'll be in a much better space. The tools to change the world are in everybody's hands. How we use them is not just up to me, it's up to all of us. This was a technology I would frequently deploy as a police officer. This technology has become outdated in our current world. It doesn't scale, it doesn't work globally, and it surely doesn't work virtually. We've seen paradigm shifts in crime and terrorism. They call for a shift to a more open form and a more participatory form of law enforcement. So I invite you to join me. After all, public safety is too important to leave to the professionals. Thank you. (Applause) (Applause)
En Estados Unidos hay 60 000 personas con marcapasos conectados a Internet. Los desfibriladores le permiten a un médico a distancia darle una descarga a un corazón en caso de que el paciente lo necesite. Pero si no lo necesita y otra persona le da una descarga, no es algo bueno. Claro, iremos más allá del cuerpo humano. Nos adentraremos en el nivel celular actual. Hasta este momento, todas las tecnologías de las que hablé están basadas en el silicio, unos y ceros, pero hay otro sistema operativo: el sistema operativo originario, el ADN. Para los ciberpiratas, el ADN es solo otro sistema operativo a ser vulnerado. Es un gran desafío para ellos. Ya hay mucha gente que trabaja para descifrar el software de la vida, y mientras la mayoría lo hace por el bien de todos, para ayudarnos, otros no lo hacen así. ¿Cómo abusarán los criminales de esto? Bueno, con la biología sintética pueden hacerse cosas muy ingeniosas. Por ejemplo, predigo que pasaremos de un mundo de drogas a base de hierbas a uno sintético. ¿Para qué necesitamos las plantas? Basta con tomar el código genético de la marihuana o de las hojas de amapola o coca, copiar y pegar los genes, colocarlos en levadura, tomar esa levadura hacerla producir la cocaína o marihuana, o cualquier droga. El uso que le daremos a la levadura en el futuro será muy interesante. De hecho, podemos hacer pan y cerveza muy especiales conforme avancemos en este próximo siglo. El costo de secuenciar el genoma humano cae precipitadamente. Seguía la Ley de Moore pero en 2008 algo cambió. Mejoró la tecnología y ahora la secuenciación de ADN sigue un ritmo cinco veces superior al de la Ley de Moore. Eso tiene para nosotros consecuencias significativas. Nos llevó 30 años pasar de la computadora personal al nivel de cibercrimen que tenemos hoy. Pero viendo lo rápido que se desarrolla la biología, y conociendo a los criminales y terroristas, podemos llegar mucho más rápido al biocrimen en el futuro. Cualquiera podrá avanzar con facilidad e imprimir su propio biovirus, versiones mejoradas del ébola o el ántrax, gripe en forma de arma. Hace poco vimos el caso de unos investigadores que obtuvieron un virus de la gripe aviar H5N1 más potente. Ya tiene una tasa de mortalidad del 70% si se lo contrae, pero es difícil de contraer. Los ingenieros, haciendo pequeños cambios genéticos, pudieron hacer con eso un arma para que sea más fácil de contraer y mueran no miles de personas, sino decenas de millones. Ya ven, se puede avanzar y crear nuevas pandemias; los investigadores que lo hicieron estaban tan orgullosos de sus logros que querían publicarlo abiertamente para que todos pudieran verlo y tener acceso a esta información. Pero va más allá de eso. El investigador del ADN, Andrew Hessel, señaló muy acertadamente que si uno puede usar el tratamiento del cáncer, el tratamiento moderno del cáncer, para atrapar una célula dejando al resto de las células intactas, entonces se puede atrapar cualquier célula de una persona. El tratamiento personalizado del cáncer es la otra cara de las bioarmas personalizadas, lo que significa que se puede atacar a cada individuo incluidas las personas de esta foto. ¿Cómo las protegeremos en el futuro? ¿Qué hacer? ¿Qué hacer con todo esto? Eso me preguntan todo el tiempo. Para mis seguidores en Twitter, tuitearé la respuesta durante el día. (Risas) En realidad, es más complejo que eso y no hay milagros. No tengo todas las respuestas, pero sé algunas cosas. A raíz del 11 de septiembre, las mejores mentes en seguridad aunaron sus innovaciones y crearon esto para la seguridad. Si esperan que la gente que creó esto los proteja de la robopocalipsis que viene... (Risas) ... eh, habría que tener un plan alternativo. (Risas) Por decir algo. Piensen en ello. (Aplausos) Hoy la aplicación de la ley es un sistema cerrado. Depende de cada nación, pero la amenaza es internacional. No se mantiene el orden a escala mundial. Al menos hasta ahora. Nuestras armas actuales, los guardias de frontera, las grandes puertas y las cercas quedaron obsoletas en el nuevo mundo en que nos movemos. ¿Cómo podemos prepararnos para estas amenazas específicas, como el ataque a un presidente o a un primer ministro? Esta sería la respuesta natural del gobierno, ocultar todos los jefes de gobierno en burbujas herméticamente selladas. Pero esto no va a funcionar. El costo de una secuencia de ADN será insignificante. Todo el mundo tendrá la suya en el futuro. Así que puede haber una manera más radical de verlo. ¿Qué tal si tomáramos el ADN del presidente, del rey o de la reina, y se lo diéramos a unas centenas de investigadores de confianza para que estudien el ADN y hagan pruebas anti-penetración para ayudar a nuestros dirigentes? ¿Y si se lo enviáramos a unos miles? O, en forma polémica y no exenta de riesgos, ¿qué tal si lo hiciéramos de dominio público? Así todos podríamos participar en la ayuda. Ya hemos visto ejemplos de esto funcionando bien. El proyecto que informa el crimen organizado y la corrupción está integrado por periodistas y ciudadanos que en colaboración voluntaria distribuida informan qué hacen los dictadores y los terroristas con los fondos públicos en el mundo. En un caso más dramático, lo hemos visto en México; un país atormentado por 50 000 asesinatos relacionados con drogas en los últimos seis años. Están matando tantas personas que ni siquiera pueden darles sepultura más que en tumbas sin nombre, como esta en las afueras de Ciudad Juárez. ¿Qué podemos hacer al respecto? El gobierno ha sido ineficaz. En México, los ciudadanos asumiendo gran riesgo, luchan para construir una solución eficaz. Están cartografiando colectivamente las actividades de los traficantes. Nos demos cuenta o no, estamos en los albores de una escalada armamentista; una carrera armamentista entre personas que usan la tecnología para el bien y aquellas que la usan para el mal. La amenaza es grave y el tiempo de actuar es ahora. Puedo asegurarles que los terroristas y los criminales lo hacen. Yo opino que en vez de tener pequeñas fuerzas de élite de agentes estatales altamente calificados que nos protejan, sería mucho mejor contar con ciudadanos comunes que aborden el problema como grupo y vean qué pueden hacer. Si todos hacemos nuestra parte creo que estaremos en un espacio mucho mejor. Las herramientas para cambiar el mundo están en manos de todos. Cómo usarlas no depende solo de mí, depende de todos nosotros. Esta era la tecnología que usaba con frecuencia como oficial de policía. Esta tecnología ha quedado obsoleta en el mundo actual. No trasciende, no funciona a nivel mundial, y, desde luego, no funciona en lo virtual. Hemos visto cambios de paradigmas en el crimen y el terrorismo. Se requiere un cambio hacia una forma más abierta y una aplicación más participativa de la ley. Por eso los invito a acompañarme. La seguridad pública es demasiado importante como para dejarla a los profesionales. Gracias. (Aplausos) (Aplausos)